Okay, so in this video then we're going to
be covering some common quality management
tools and these are
just some tools that you
just need to know
about at a very high level.
There are some other separate videos on
some of the other quality management tools
that you need to know in a bit more
detail.
So these ones you just need to know at
very, very high level.
Okay, we're just going to be mentioning
them.
So one of the tools I want to mention in
this one called the quality audit, right?
And quality audit, it's
an audit, therefore it's a
process, and therefore this
refers to quality assurance.
And in fact, it's a tooling technique
specifically in the managed quality process.
Now, quality audit then is a structured
review and independent review of the
entire project process, right,
of the entire, you know, basically it's
making sure that the team is doing what
they're supposed to be doing.
So a structured independent
review to ensure the project
activities comply with processes,
policies, and procedures.
So in other words, is the team doing what
they're supposed to be doing?
Are procedures being followed?
Six Sigma standards are they being
followed?
ISO standards are they being followed?
When you're building a house, when you're
constructing a building, are the
appropriate code standards, you know,
building codes being followed?
So it's just making sure
then that everything is, you
know, the team is doing what
they're supposed to be doing.
Now, let's think about this.
What is an audit?
Just like any audit, whether it's a
financial audit or any other kind of audit.
Generally, an audit is basically making
sure that the team has followed procedures.
Generally, an audit is done after the
fact.
So it's making sure that the
team has followed procedures
in order to determine that the
team is following procedures.
Exactly the same thing here regarding the
quality audit.
As with any audit, you're
looking at a transaction
and seeing how it's
flowing through the process.
It's making sure there's a paper trail.
Exactly the same thing here as well.
And it's looking at the entire project
process.
Remember you're building quality into your
entire project process.
It's not just looking at the testing of
the product, that's just one part.
Are procedures being followed for testing
the product, but it's looking at the,
like said, the entire project process,
every single procedure.
Even things like, for example,
change control procedures,
documentation procedures,
sign-off procedures.
So like, for example,
change control procedures,
are change control
procedures being followed?
Somebody has identified the need for a
change.
Are we doing an impact analysis?
Then are we submitting to the change
control board?
In fact, first of all, has it been
documented?
Somebody requested a change, has that
actually been documented?
Where's the documentation?
Did we do an impact analysis?
Did we submit to the change control board?
Did the change control board approve or
reject it?
If they approved it, did we implement that
change?
Once we implemented that change,
did you actually test that change?
Did somebody sign off on that change?
So it's making sure all procedures are
being followed.
all project procedures and ideally it
should be an independent review generally
an audit is somebody independent somebody
outside of the project right or somebody
outside of the project team they don't
necessarily need to be outside of the
organization but somebody outside of the
project team there's usually there's
somebody outside independently could be
verifying all of these procedures so
that's one tool another
tool I want to briefly
mention of this one
called process analysis.
Process analysis really just refers to
continuous improvement.
So it's identifying inefficient processes,
ineffective processes, and then just
seeing how we can make improvements to
them.
And so really, as a
project manager, we should
always be in a continuous
improvement process.
We should always be looking at ways to
improve our procedures.
That's just all part of being proactive.
Now, process analysis here doesn't refer
to six sigma process improvement, right?
That's something completely separate.
That's an organization-wide thing.
Here we're talking about just specifically
for your project.
Procedures need improving.
We need to improve some of these
processes.
Another tool is this one called
statistical sampling.
A statistical sampling
is essentially testing
a representative sample of the population.
So you're testing a representative sample
of the population.
You're not testing every single item out
there.
And the whole principle behind this is to
reduce the number of testing without
reducing the quality of the scope of the
test.
So is a very simple example.
Back in my HR days, we would be
implementing, say, a payroll system.
We want to test the payroll deduction for
a Fortune 500 client.
Now, this Fortune 500 client may have,
for example, 200,000 employees.
We want to test the payroll deduction
functionality so that the correct payroll
deductions are taken from each employee's
payroll right at the
appropriate payroll cycle.
They've got 200,000 employees.
We're not going to test every single one.
I'm not going to test all 200,000
employees.
I know.
We're going to take a representative
sample of each population of employees,
based on their function, based on whether
they're part-time, full-time, based on
whether they're, say, trade
union workers or non-trade union
workers, based on their location
and of many, many, many factors.
But we're going to take a representative
sample of each population of employee and
then test on that representative sample,
right?
Just take a handful, maybe five,
ten, however many, and then test on them.
We're not going to test, not going to do
200,000 tests.
So that's what statistical sampling really
is.
Testing, a representative sample,
reducing the number of tests, right?
But we're not going to reduce the quality
of the test or the scope of the testing.
All right, so another tool then is this
one called the SIPOC model.
And a SIPOC model is a type of flow chart.
And Again, we're just going to talk about
this very briefly, right?
They generally, you know, you probably
won't be asked to interpret flowchart,
but, I mean, there's, you might be able
to, you might ask you, but usually they,
usually they won't.
But it's a type of flowchart.
And a flowchart is a
tool and technique, and
a SIPOP model is an
example of a flowchart.
And really, what I would do is I would
just learn what SIPOC stands for.
It stands for supplier, input,
process, output, customer.
That's what it stands for.
supplier, input, process, output,
customer.
Another tool, DFX, design for X,
right?
Where X stands for excellence,
design for excellence.
And this is generally used a lot in
manufacturing.
And X is a wild card that could represent
many, many different factors, such as
safety, reliability, cost, 6 Sigma,
you know, many others.
These are just three examples.
And essentially what we're doing here is
this product is being designed for safety.
So we are designing this product
specifically for safety or this product is
specifically being designed for
reliability.
Or this product is specifically being
designed for cost.
Right.
We need to reduce the cost.
So that's a very, very simple example.
And again, it's an entire methodology.
You can be doing an entire class on this,
right?
But you just need to know,
just a very, very, you know,
just need to know that
it's there, that it exists.
Same with this one here, a matrix diagram.
And a matrix diagram is a chart showing
relationship between different variables,
right?
And, you know, relationship between
different quality variables.
Most common type is something called the
house of quality.
And basically the way it's doing is really
just at a very, very high level.
you identify what the customer wants,
where identify the customer the
requirements, and then you want to
identify how different variables can
satisfy the customer's
needs, right, different
variables that can impact the quality.
And remember, definition of
quality, degree to which the
set of the inherent
characteristics fulfills requirements.
So we're identifying the customers of
requirements and then seeing all the
different factors that can fulfill those
requirements.
And again, very, very high, level.
I mean, matrix diagram again, is an entire
topic, entire class all by itself,
which you don't really need to know for
the PMP exam.
You just need to, you know, not know that
it's there.
Most common type, like I said,
is this one called the House of Quality.
Now, another tool then is this one called
a scatter diagram.
And a scatter diagram is showing an actual
correlation between two variables.
If you want to show a correlation between
two variables.
These variables are known as a dependent
variable and an independent variable.
So, the very simple example, right?
I have a simple little example here.
Let's say, you know, it's, you've got
really bad weather, it's constantly raining.
So will the increase in number of rainy
days, will that increase umbrella sales?
Is there a direct correlation between the
number of rainy days and umbrella sales.
And, you know, if you want to show a
correlation, then we would
use a scatter diagram.
And a scatter diagram, then you've got all
these different scatter points here.
If they're all trending in one direction
here, they're all trending.
You can all see trending in a diagonal
form here.
Then it shows that there is going to be
some kind of correlation there.
Now, you have to have a dependent,
variable and an independent variable,
in order for it to truly have any kind of
meaning.
Right.
So umbrella sales is dependent on the
number of rainy days.
Umbrella sales is dependent.
It's a dependent variable.
It's dependent on the number of rainy
days.
Not the other way around.
If we suddenly start
selling more umbrellas,
that's not going to cause
it to rain more, right?
So it doesn't work both ways.
It only works one way.
If there's an increase in the
number of rainy days, then
that's what's going to cause
an increase in umbrella sales.
So umbrella sales then is dependent on the
number of rainy days.
So that's what a scatter diagram is
useful, right, to show an actual
correlation between an X and a Y,
between two variables.
So these are just some of the additional
tools, some of the common basic tools that
you, you know, that you, that you,
need to know for quality management.
But there are a few other
tools that we are covering
that you need to know
in a little bit more detail.
And these are all covered in separate
videos.